

Having 5 years of experience in IT. Experience with SQL Server and T-SQL in designing Tables, user functions, views, Indexes, joins, sub queries and Stored Procedures.knowledge in data warehouse concepts.



ETL process using SSIS, SSRS report generation

Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Current Designation: Software Engineer

Current Company: Accenture Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: sql server development,ssis,msbi,data warehousing,ssas,t-sql,power bi,alteryx

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jul-20 Last Modified: 10-Feb-20

Summary

A competent professional with over 5 years of rich experience in IT having good experience in software development, design, testing, implementation and maintenance of various applications using TSQL. Expert knowledge in designing and developing complex applications. Proposed design patterns and emerging technologies to support application development projects.

- Currently working in Mahindra Comviva as a Software Engineer since November 2015.
- Worked in Universal Electronics Pvt Ltd Bangalore as a Software Engineer since March 2013 to Nov 2015.
- Experience of providing training to new joiners on TSQL

Work Experience

Accenture as Software Engineer Apr 2017 to Till Date

- SQL Server 2012 database. Creating ETL packages using SSIS. Managed performance and tuning of SQL queries and fixed the slow running queries in production.
- Worked heavily with relationship database models, schemas & entity-relationship diagrams (ERMs) to create technical/system design documents.
- Load the data from MS Excel to Table and table to MS Excel.
- Loaded the data using the SQL loader, Imports based on file formats.
- T-SQL Scripting for Stored Procedures, Functions, Triggers and complex queries for reporting purposes. Code review, query tuning, source control and release management.
- System/unit testing and SQL code reviews.
- Provide database coding to support business applications using SQL server.
- Working in the domain of product based company (Remote controls database).

Mahindra Comviva as Software Engineer

Nov 2015 to Apr 2017

- Designing and developing the SSIS Packages.
- Working with Dataflow Task, Executes Sql Task frequently.
- Configuration changes on existing application.
- Co-ordinate with all the other Vendor teams to ensure a smooth flow of implementation.

Universal Electronics Pvt Ltd as SQL Developer

Mar 2013 to Nov 2015

- Analysing and Understanding the business requirements
- Designed and developing SSIS packages using different transformations like Conditional Split, Multicast, Union-All, Merge, Merge Join and Derived Column.
- Written user defined functions and stored procedures. Debugging and tuning the procedures.
- Populating the Data from different source systems into DW using SSIS.
- Created Unit test cases and Implemented unit test results.
- Involved in the design of Data-warehouse using Star-Schema methodology and converted data from various sources to tables.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from vtu university in 2012

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
TSQL	2005/8/12	2019	5 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
SSIS	2012	2019	4 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
SSRS	ver-3/4	2016	2 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Power BI		0	0 Year(s) 5 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			
Kannada	Proficient			
Tamil	Proficient			

Projects

Project Title: CDW Client: CDW

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2018 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: CDW (Computer Discount Warehouse) is a leading multi-brand technology solutions provider to business,

government, education and healthcare organizations in the United States.

Project Title: ACBD Manager Tool

Client: UEI

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Sep 2013 - Jun 2014 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Project Location: Bangalore

Team Size: 5 Role: Programmer

Skill Used: TSQL,SSIS,SSRS

Role Description: Designed the database.

Loading the data from different source like excel and XML files by using SSIS

Creating the stored procedures.

Generating the report.

Project Details: ACDB manger tool involves getting the information about the different brands of AC and load those information to the database.

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

US Work Status: Need H1 Visa

Countries: United States Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time